让我们重申一下这个问题。我们想要从姿势A平滑地移动末端效应器姿势
Let's restate the problem. We want to move the end effector pose smoothly from pose A
我们现在要做的是确定末端执行器的姿势
to pose B. What we're going to do now is to determine the pose of the end effector at
每个中间点。我们有一个插值函数，它的参数是最初的姿势，
each intermediate point. We have an interpolation function, its arguments are the initial pose,
最终姿势和标量变量S从0到1平滑变化。结果
the final pose and a scalar variable S which vary smoothly from 0 to 1. The result of this
功能是机器人末端执行器的中间姿势。对于这些中间体中的每一个
function is the intermediate pose of the robot's end effector. For each of these intermediate
姿势我们将应用逆运动学函数来确定关节角度
poses we're going to apply the inverse kinematic function to determine the joint angles that
对应于S的特定值。
corresponds to that particular value of S.
总而言之，我们正在做的是在每个时间步骤中我们将进行插值
So in summary what we're doing is that in every time step we're going to interpolate
使用顶部方程的帖子。然后我们将执行反向运动学。这个
the post using the top equation. Then we're going to perform inverse kinematics. This
是一种与我们在前一种情况下使用的算法不同的算法。以前我们插入
is a different algorithm than what we used in the previous case. Previously we interpolated
关节角度。在这种情况下，我们实际上是插入笛卡尔姿势。本来打算
the joint angles. In this case we're actually interpolating the Cartesian pose. We're going
继续我们从上一个例子中离开的地方继续我们现在要做什么
to carry on from where we left off from the previous example. What we're going to do now
是笛卡尔插值运动。我将创建一个新的工作区变量TS。这个
is Cartesian interpolated motion. I am going to create a new workspace variable TS. This
是插值的笛卡尔姿势。我将使用函数ctraj作为笛卡尔轨迹
is the interpolated Cartesian pose. I'm going to use the function ctraj for Cartesian trajectory
我将分阶段进行初始姿势，最终姿势和时间步数，创建
I am going to phase in the initial pose, the final pose and the number of time steps, create
我们工作区中的一个名为TS的新变量。我们可以看到这是一个三维的
a new variable in our workspace called TS. We can see that this is a three dimensional
矩阵，四行，四列和50个平面。所以我们可以把它想象成一组4x4矩阵
matrix, four rows, four columns and 50 planes. So we can imagine as a set of 4x4 matrices
一个堆叠在另一个之上。最终维度表明我们正在谈论的特定时间步骤。
stacked one above the other. The final dimension indicates which particular time step we're talking about.
让我们看看第一个元素的所有行和所有列。那是
Let's have a look at the, all the rows and all the columns of the first element. That's
最初的姿势。我们可以看第二个姿势和第三个姿势等等。现在我能
the initial pose. We can look at the second pose and the third pose and so on. Now I can
实际上将这个三维矩阵相位成逆运动函数。逆
actually phase this three dimensional matrix into the inverse kinematic function. Inverse
具有6个关节和球形手腕的机器人的运动学。我打算通过TS。
kinematics for a robot with 6 joints and a spherical wrist. I'm going to pass in TS.
它要做的是计算该矩阵中每个姿势的关节角度。所以
What it's going to do is to compute the joint angles for every pose in this matrix. So the
结果现在QS，我们可以看到一个包含50行和6列的矩阵。这是计算的，
result now QS, we can see is a matrix with 50 rows and 6 columns. It's computed, the
逆运动学，对于矩阵TS中的每个单独姿势。我们可以回过头来看看
inverse kinematics, for every single pose in the matrix TS. And we can go back to figure
1，我们可以绘制。看看它的样子。这是笛卡尔插值运动。
1 and we can plot that. See what it looks like. This is the Cartesian interpolated motion.
回到图2，我们可以绘制对应于笛卡尔坐标的关节角度
And coming back to figure 2 we can plot the joint angles corresponding to that Cartesian
运动。我们可以看到它们与我们从关节插值得到的轨迹大致相似
motion. We can see that they are broadly similar to the trajectory that we got from joint interpolated
运动。它们肯定以相同的值开始和结束，但沿着中间的路径
motion. They certainly start and end at the same values but the path along the middle
他们遵循的轨迹略有不同。这种差异足以改变
of the trajectory, they follow is slightly different. That difference is enough to change
从3D空间略微弯曲到3D空间中的直线运动。
the motion from being slightly curved in 3D space to being a straight line in 3D space.
这是笛卡尔插值策略的结果。在这里我们可以看到机器人关节
This is the result of the Cartesian interpolation strategy. Here we can see the robot joint
角度在两秒钟内从初始姿势平滑变化到最终姿势。
angles varying smoothly from the initial pose to the final pose over a period of two seconds.
如果我从每个中间关节角度计算前向运动学和
If I compute the forward kinematics from each of the intermediate set of joint angles and
绘制x坐标与y坐标的关系。我现在可以看到机器人末端效应器
plot the x coordinate versus the y coordinate. I can see now that the robot end effector
是从A到B的完全直线移动
is moving in a perfectly straight line from A to B.
如果我现在将正向运动学函数应用于所有中间关节角度组，
If I now apply forward kinematic function to all the intermediate sets of joint angles,
我可以确定机器人末端执行器的姿势。如果我绘制末端效应器x坐标
I can determine the pose of the robot end effector. If I plot the end effector x coordinate
相对于它的y坐标，我可以看到末端效应器现在已经完美地移动了
against its y coordinate, I can see that the end effector has now moved in a perfectly
从姿势A到姿势B的直线。
straight line from pose A to pose B.
同样地，当我看到末端执行器的方向时，我可以看到音高
Similarly when I look at the orientation of the end effector I can see that the pitch
并且在轨迹的整个持续时间内，红豆杉角度等于0。所以工具方向
and yew angles are equal to 0 for the entire duration of the trajectory. So the tool orientation
保持不变，刀尖已沿直线移动。
remains constant and the tool tip has moved in a straight line.
我们只是通过改变插值或插值笛卡尔的方式来实现这一点
We achieved this just by changing the way we do the interpolation or interpolating Cartesian
姿势而非机器人关节角度。如果我们比较两组关节角度轨迹，
poses rather than robot joint angles. If we compare the two sets of joint angle trajectories,
我们可以看到它们实际上非常相似。实际上没有太大的变化
we can see that they're actually quite similar. There is actually not very much variation
在关节角度作为实现这种直线末端所需的时间的函数
in the joint angles as a function of time necessary to achieve this straight line end
效应器运动与抑制末端执行器运动。
effector motion versus the curbed end effector motion.